

linkedin.com/in/rodasnetwork San Francisco, CA 94112



Personal Summary

In the U.S. Marine Corps I served as a Data Systems Specialist during my five year military career. Since re-entering the workforce I have done contract work in information and systems management. I also completed a brief program for Computer Network Technology at the City College in San Francisco and studied Web Design and New Media at Academy of Art University.

The Marines taught me discipline and professionalism, now I am taking time to focus attention on learning to Domain Driven Design for developing Web Applications with strong User Experience. My success has been achieved thanks to team cooperation while working towards a common mission. Thus far my career has been a rewarding experience; here is a summary of what I have learned.

Skills

Web Developer

- ✓ C#, Java, PHP, and MySQL / MSSQL / NoSQL
- ✓ *Object-oriented style programming (OOP)*
- ✓ Design Patterns
- ✓ User Experience / User Interface Design
- ✓ Build full-featured web applications using model view controller (MVC) framework
- ✓ CSS3 Animations, AngularJS library and AJAX technologies
- ✓ Responsive Design with HTML, CSS, and Media Quires
- ✓ Real-time web application development using ASP.NET Core and Signal R

Systems Administration

- ✓ Domain Name Service (DNS) configuration
- ✓ Load Balancing
- ✓ Network Routing / Switcing / VLANs
- ✓ Information Internet Services (IIS) / Nginx / Apache web server configuration
- ✓ Database management for MariaDB 10 (MySQL) or Microsoft SQL Server (MSSQL) or MongoDB (NoSQL)
- ✓ Linux / Windows Server
- ✓ Hyper-V Virtualization
- ✓ Linux Containers
- ✓ Azure Cloud Services / Online Cloud Servers

Experience

ASP.NET Core / C# Developer

TiliPay.com — San Francisco, CA. 2016 - Present

- ∞ Developed mobile friendly web application to split and keep track of bill payments among roommates.
- ∞ Designed user flow, software charts, and user experience detailed mockup.
- ∞ Coded using ASP.NET Core MVC along with a Service Oriented Architechture (SOA).
- ∞ Build and deployed ASP.NET Core application to Azure Cloud Service.

Creative Director

MBTSR.com — San Francisco, CA. 2012 – 2013

- ∞ Conduct research on new technology analyzing benefits and costs to organizational products.
- ∞ Designed landing page, blog, and private customer dashboard for an online classroom.
- ∞ Created multimedia assets like photography, vector art, and CSS designs for company website.
- ∞ Built customer feedback system for web app using a Restful JavaScript and PHP method.
- ∞ Deployed server services Gitolite, Apache2, Java and MySQL for a Wicket web application.

PHP Web Application Developer

American Land Surveying, Inc — San Francisco, CA. 2012 - 2013

- ∞ Migrated a local Microsoft Access Database into an online PHP and MySQL web application.
- ∞ Developed web dashboard to track new business leads, and manage legal contracts, employees and contacts, assign calendared tasks, and account for payment transactions.
- Designed custom rich HTML forms for users to dynamically interact with companies' products and services.

Page 1 of 3

Experience continued

Helpdesk Administrator

ITT System Division — Camp Victory, Iraq. 2008 - 2009

- ∞ Solved complex data processing issues with specific solutions for each costumer by phone and remote assistance technology.
- ∞ Administered over 20,000 Active Directory accounts, groups, contacts and MS Exchange mailboxes using a MMC 3.0 console as well as a consolidated library of process documents.
- ∞ Primary support and interface with site Information Management Officers to ensure all Helpdesk resources.
- ∞ Worked closely with Information Assurance (IA) department to verify integrity of all network documents, including proper signatures for proper security clearance level to access DoD network resources.

Cisco Network Engineer

National Oceanic Atmospheric Association (NOAA) — Silver Spring, MD. 2008

- ∞ Upgraded 7200 enterprise central routers to new Juniper J series routers that connected five branch offices with T1 leased lines.
- ∞ Once a week maintenance window after normal business hours to perform necessary network upgrades and do a full test of network integrity, including testing all services and failover tests.
- ∞ Tier 3 support for network users
- ∞ Administration of VPN remote accounts.
- ∞ Provided maintenance in a 1,000+ node campus network with 7200, 6500, 4000 Cisco platforms.
- ∞ Maintained a multi-VLAN environment with OSPF topology routers and remote office branches.
- ∞ Daily SNMP traps reporting of all remote office routers and corporate switches with Syslog server.
- ∞ Weekly meetings with entire IT department to discuss ongoing network issues and status.
- ∞ Lead CiscoWorks engineer for LMS 2.1 migration to automated LMS 3.1 SNMP Unix monitoring system.
- ∞ Implemented NAC/CNA framework for security solution to enterprise network to comply with Cisco's recommended best practices.

Infrastructure/Network Engineer

2nd Marine Logistics Group FWD — Camp Al Taggadum, Iraq. 2007 - 2008

- ∞ Served as lead technician for planning new installations, configurations, and maintenance of data communication network projects.
- ∞ Managed an Active Directory domain and managed all Cisco Systems switches and routers on a military forward operating base in Iraq.
- ∞ Maintained 100% uptime for DataPath Inc. LSWAN and WPPL systems on Camp Habbaniyah.
- ∞ Conducted site analysis to determine specific needs for expansion of the production network.
- $\, \infty \,$ Held a lead position for configuring and troubleshooting secure VoIP phones.

Experience continued

Systems Network Administrator

2nd Marine Logistics Group, Communications Co. — Camp Lejeune, NC. 2005 - 2007

- ∞ Reviewed and implemented key changes to IT directives while providing continuous development of organizational IT policy and procedures.
- ∞ Provided training on General Dynamics equipment, server builds, network configuration and security for IT department.
- ∞ Conducted testing for new DataPath Inc. satellite communication prototypes that were used in Operation Iraqi Freedom Campaign.
- ∞ Responsible for maintaining accountability of data equipment valued at over \$1,000,000.
- $\,\infty\,$ Maintained sever health for domain controllers and trusts between Windows NT and Windows 2003 Active Directory.
- ∞ Administered more than 1,000 Active Directory accounts with Exchange mailboxes with Outlook Web Access on both secret classified and unclassified networks.
- ∞ Maintained and supported all computers, software, and hardware issues for all network users.

Data Network Specialist

III Marine Expeditionary Force — Okinawa, Japan. 2003 - 2005

- ∞ Manage unit's accounts in a Windows NT 4.0 and Exchange 5.5 environment for entire Okinawa Island.
- ∞ Provided Outlook Web Access and RASS support for remote users.
- ∞ End-user computer applications helpdesk support for customers and troubleshooting.
- ∞ Performed Systematic Antivirus Corporate Edition daily updates, diagnostic and troubleshooting.
- ∞ Deployed network systems for Military Operations in Philippines, Thailand, and Korea.

Education

Academy of Art University, San Francisco, CA. A.F.A. Web Design and New Media, December 2016

City College of San Francisco, San Francisco, CA. A.S. Social Behavioral Science, December 2012

Marine Corps Communications-Electronic School, 29 Palms, CA. Data Systems Supervisors Course, summer 2006

DataPath Inc, Camp Lejeune, NC. Advanced Logistics Support WAN Training (LSWAN), January 2006

Marine Corps Communications-Electronic School, 29 Palms, CA. Data Network Specialist Program, December 2003